Here in just a moment,
our meeting has started and the recording
has started.
Good morning, everyone.
We are letting everybody on into the room,
so I'll probably repeat myself a little
bit and my apologies for that.
As most everybody knows,
I'm Dominic Zerlo and I'm the Director
for the Center for Medical Cannabis and
Psilocybin.
This is the Patient Qualification and
Safety Committee meeting with the Chair
of Ian Dunn.
Just as a reminder,
this meeting is being recorded,
so Please ensure that you're using
appropriate language during the meeting
so we don't have to go back and bleep it
out later on when when we post it up on
the website.
I did actually want to make sure to
mention one thing with regard to the
program and the advisory Board's websites
and that is the Department of Health and
actually Allstate agencies are in the
process of converting everything over
into into ADA compliance.
And so some of the documents which may
not necessarily be,
may briefly not be available on the
website.
If that does happen and it is a document
that you know was there previously,
please be aware that we are working on
converting everything and things will be
set back on up.
But if there is a document that you need
in the meantime,
you are welcome to reach out to the
program.
But please give it a little bit of time
if it's not something you need right away,
simply because we don't want to get
overwhelmed with a request for something
that may just be back on the website in
an in a couple of days or so.
So just to let everybody know that is
coming up,
I believe the anticipated date at this
point right now is on the 24th to the
26th that that may occur.
So just as a note,
if you go to the website during those
days, later in those days,
you may experience that little bit of
difficulty saying,
I know I saw this year before,
where is it?
And again,
this is the Advisory Board committee
meeting for patient qualification and
safety.
And I will now turn it over to the chair,
Ian Dunn.
Ian,
good morning and the meeting is yours.
Good morning, everyone.
Thank you for taking time out of your
Monday.
Happy 420 everyone.
We are going to be working on a few
things today.
In the patient Qualification and Safety
committee.
We are going to look at patient
information safety.
It was brought up in another committee
that we hadn't taken the time to
specifically apply HIPAA.
So we are going to go ahead and do that.
After that, if time permits,
we'll be looking at petition submission
processes to be adopted by the Board and
then evidence reviews standards for
qualifying conditions if time permits.
I will now turn over to some
introductions.
Thank you for attending today's meeting.
Please share.
That was not great.
Thank you for attending today's meeting.
Please share your name,
your area of expertise relating to
patient qualification and safety,
and what brings you to the patient
qualification meeting.
At this time,
if you would like to introduce yourselves
and participate, please raise your hand.
All right.
And 1st, we've got sky, rivers and sky.
I've enabled your mic.
You can unmute when ready.
You can hear me OK?
Yes.
Oh, hi, I'm Sky Rivers.
I'm with the Santa Fe Reporter.
I'm a retired intuitive counselor.
I have been following the committees and
the latest updates on what is going on.
And I appreciate everybody's attendance
and all the work that the DoH and
everyone has been putting in.
And thank you for having me.
So thanks Sky.
And let's see, next we've got Kate Hawk.
And OK, I have enabled your mic.
You can unmute when ready.
Yeah.
Good morning, everybody.
I've introduced myself a few times in
these meetings.
I'm going to say I'm Kate Hawk.
I live in Santa Fe,
been a MAPS member since the 80s,
trauma therapist all these years.
And I'll just mention right now I'm in
Scottsdale.
I've been working with Scottsdale
Research Institute doing their FDA phase
one study.
We just saw a group of 8 veterans through
a mushroom session and it's going really
well.
So glad to be here today.
Awesome.
Thanks, Kate.
And next we've got Chris Peskowski and
you can unmute when ready.
Good morning, Mr.
Chair.
Good morning, everybody.
I'm Chris Peskowski,
veteran facilitator in Colorado,
and I'm just happy to be here and help.
Thank you.
All right.
And next we've got Brenda Burgard.
And Brenda, you can unmute.
Good morning, everyone.
I'm Brenda Burgard.
I'm one of the Chair people for training
and education and also President of
Decrim here in New Mexico.
I welcome everybody here and I hope this
will be a really productive and helpful
meeting.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Thanks, Brenda.
And next we've got Gregory Evans.
And Gregory, you can unmute when ready.
Good morning, everybody.
My name is Gregory Evans.
I'm an independent researcher mycologist
with no affiliations.
I'm Sankei resident and my intention is
to support the programs development
through committee recommendations aligned
with emerging research and best practices.
Thank you all and good morning.
All righty, good morning to everyone.
What if you will bring up the patient
information safety?
This is going to be a very basic document.
I it's just basically mirroring HIPAA
onto the program.
The purpose?
To protect patient safety and ensure
program integrity and promote equitable
access to care by establishing clear
confidentiality standards for all
licensed entities participating in the
medical psilocybin program.
So our recommendation is to the Board
that they adopt these standards.
So our HIPAA Alliance standards.
Licensees should implement and adhere to
privacy protections consistent with the
standards established under the Health
Insurance Portability and Accountability
Act of 1996,
regardless of whether the licensee
qualifies as a covered entity under
federal law.
Licensees should not use or disclose
patient identifying information except as
permitted or required under HIPAA aligned
privacy standards or pursuant to valid
legal process, including a court order,
warrant, or lawfully issued subpoena.
Licensees should not disclose patient
information in response to informal,
voluntary or non compulsory requests,
including requests from law enforcement
that are not supported by valid legal
process.
The minimum necessary standard is that
all disclosures should be limited to the
minimum necessary information required to
comply with applicable legal requirement.
We're not prohibited by law.
Licensee should make reasonable efforts
to notify patients prior to disclosure of
their information.
These requirements should apply to all
patients facing licensed,
all patient facing licensed entities
within the medical psilocybin program
regardless of federal HIPAA status.
All right.
And then there is a question from Dominic
Zerlo.
Yes, good morning, Ian.
Just as a clarification,
I would recommend taking out the year of
the ACT because there are updates
regularly and I would recommend adding in
not just having HIPAA,
so not just having that there,
but also listing high tech,
which is the health information
technology for economic and clinical
health and ensuring that that is there.
Just as a note,
that is something that the department
does require under with regard to
anything that individuals and and
programs all are actually are,
are compliant with regard to this because
it is a federal level.
The main reason for needing it within
here is because psilocybin is still a
schedule 1,
so technically illicit at the federal
level.
So we just want to make sure though that
all of the health security issues and
requirements are actually there as well.
So so I would yeah.
And I see it's already,
you're already changing it to add high
tech.
So that would be perfect.
Thank you.
All right.
Any other questions, comments,
concerns on the information standards?
Perfect.
Then let's go ahead and move to a vote.
All those in favor,
please raise your hand at this time.
All right.
We've got four hands up.
Thank you.
And then please place your hand down at
this time.
And then if you are opposed,
please raise your hand 4 yeses, 0 Nos.
The Patient Information Safety document
is adopted by the committee.
Next,
we can move on to the patient petition
submission process.
So the purpose and initial implementation.
So,
to prevent program overload at initial
implementation,
the Committee recommends that the Board
not begin accepting petitions until
February 28th of 2027.
Prior to the acceptance of petitions,
the Patient Qualification and Safety
Committee should evaluate potential
qualifying conditions and PRIDE provide
the Board with an initial set of
expansionary qualifying conditions
recommendations no later than January
31st, 2027.
Once the Board begins accepting petitions,
the Medical Psilocybin Advisory Board may
accept and review petitions from any
individual or association individual of
individuals requesting the addition of a
qualifying condition under the Medical
Psilocybin Act.
Except as otherwise provided,
they shall be submitted electronically to
the Department of Health with basic
instructions to try and help them out
with organizing and making sure that they
get it.
So a specific subject line, just saying,
petition to the Medical Psilocybin
Advisory Board and beginning with Deer
Medical Psilocybin Advisory Board.
That way it's searchable in their system
for submission deadlines.
I'm not gonna lie,
I ripped these off of the medical
cannabis program.
The complete petitions may be submitted
at any time following that.
January 31st, 20270.
Sorry it was February 28th.
This was the wrong number.
Petitions will be scheduled for review at
the next available Board meeting.
To be considered,
petitions must be received at least 30
calendar days prior to the scheduled
meeting and to ensure inclusion in the
public notice,
petitions must be received at least 35
calendar days prior to the Board meeting
to be processed.
Imported to the Board.
Petitions must be submitted in a readable
electronic format including the following,
a caption including their name, address,
contact information,
the medical condition,
medical treatment or disease pros
proposed for inclusion,
a table of contents,
an introductory narrative,
a statement of proposed benefit,
supporting evidence,
and additional materials.
As an optional.
I will go ahead and paste that into the
chat and I will open up for discussion,
questions, comments, concerns.
All right.
And 1st, we've got Kate Hawk.
Kate, you can unmute when you're ready.
Thank you.
Yeah, I think I understand this,
but just to make sure it's totally clear
to everybody.
So this is just for adding additional
conditions to the four that are already
approved, right?
So it's gives us a chance to get started
with what's already in the act,
and then there will be opportunities to
add other things afterwards.
Is that correct?
Yeah.
So it does two things.
So we can begin as a committee evaluating
qualifications now,
But what it says is like if we're gonna
individually submit petitions,
that would begin a little bit later,
but like the committee will still discuss
some initial qualifying conditions to
provide the board.
And then after that process,
the board will begin accepting petitions
as like the standard protocol outside of
the committees.
OK, thank you.
All right.
And next we've got sky,
rivers and sky you can unmute when
already.
OK.
Looks like might be having some issues.
I know that earlier you were able to
introduce yourself.
Yeah, there you go.
OK, there I am.
What was just discussed,
does that mean that the implementation
date December of the end of this year is
going to be moved up to January of next
year or this petition is just for
additional qualifying conditions?
I'm a little confused.
Yeah,
so this would be for additional
qualifying conditions.
Basically what this would do is the
original implementation date or goal by
the department would stand.
This would just say, OK,
so if they're going to start in December,
then that gives us two months to allow
them to figure out the current systems
and processes for those initial patients
and then we can begin to add to that
patient pool.
I just don't want to stress out the
systems on the very first day.
OK, Thank you very much.
Thank you.
All right, any other questions, comments,
concerns?
All righty,
then we will move to a vote of this
document as well.
All those in favor,
please raise your hand at this time.
All right and I'm seeing six hands up
perfect.
You may lower your hands at this time and
all those opposed please raise your hand
at this time.
All right, seeing none in opposition.
This is document also is adopted by the
committee.
Now we have one final one which is going
to discuss.
So that had qualifying conditions added
in two processes.
So the later one once the program is in
effect will be the petitions.
But the initial one where we're still
gonna review and collect data is gonna be
the patient qualification and safety
committee.
So next we're gonna review our standards
for qualifying conditions in this
committee, this one.
And Jorge,
would you do me a favor and go ahead and
paste it in the chat?
I sure will.
Thank you.
So the purpose is to ensure that
recommendations for new qualifying
conditions under the medical psilocybin
program are based on credible scientific
evidence,
clinical relevance and patients patient
safety considerations.
So this policy would govern the
evaluation of potential qualifying
conditions by the Patient Qualification
and Safety Committee.
So the standard of evidence,
randomized controlled trials shall be
considered the strongest and most
reliable form of evidence for evaluating
therapeutic benefit and shall be
prioritized when available.
In the absence of sufficient randomized
controlled trial data,
the committee may reconsider high quality
observational studies, open label trials,
and other emerging evidence.
Provided that limitations are clearly
acknowledged and the totality of evidence
supports a reasonable expectation of
benefit and safety.
Systemic reviews and analysis may be used
to evaluate consistency and overall
trends in the evidence.
The committee saw ensure that such
analysis are not given duplicate weight
by where they rely on the same underlying
studies already under review.
In applying the standard of evidence,
the committee shall consider the strength
and consistency of findings across these
studies,
the size and clinical relevance of
observed effects,
known or potential risks associated with
treatment,
and the severity of the condition and
availability of alternative treatments.
Questions, comments, concerns.
Let's see,
Chris was just asking in the chat if we
could zoom into the document a bit and
then that looks like.
How does that look?
It's also in the chat.
It's a little better.
Thank you.
Yeah, sure.
All right.
And Kate,
you can unmute when you're ready.
Yeah, Thank you.
Well, this generally makes sense,
but I'm thinking in from a perspective of
end of life care, for instance.
I'd like a little more time to have a
chance to talk about it.
We're going to have an in person meeting
this week and I'd just like to, you know,
these are really important to set the
foundation.
I'd just like a little more time for us
to take this into our committee and
consider, you know,
what would the implications be for end of
life care particularly?
So, you know,
just wondering if we can have a little
more time before we vote on this.
I yes,
we can if we need to take more time.
So I don't see how.
So end of life care is already a
qualifying condition.
It's a legislative 1.
So this would just go for additional
qualifying conditions or OK yeah,
so I didn't understand.
So this is just the additional ones this
doesn't apply for.
I guess end of life care isn't as clearly
defined.
I mean, it's not a, you know,
a diagnosis or disorder in in in itself,
but OK, so this is just additional ones.
If there's evidence,
we want to have evidence to add anything
additional, right?
Anything the legislature didn't add,
we want to take the time to make sure
we're reviewing evidence.
Got it.
OK,
Just didn't understand this is only for
additional things.
Thank you.
No worries.
Thank you.
Any other questions, comments or concerns?
All righty,
let's go ahead and move on to a vote of
how we the petition.
No, the evidence requirements,
all those in favor,
please raise your hand at this time.
All right, seeing four hands up.
All righty,
at this time you may lower your hands.
All righty.
And then if you are opposed,
please raise your hand at this time
seeing none, the vote for yes, zero, no,
the document is adopted.
So next what I want to do is go ahead and
plan for some qualifying conditions that
we think would be beneficial.
That way at our next meeting,
we can compile evidence and, you know,
get prepared for that part as well.
But I do want to just open before we
start that.
Any other things that you feel need to be
addressed before we moving on to this
qualifying conditions section?
Gregory.
Yeah, this goes back to the HIPAA.
Just really quick before we move on.
I wanted to get my words right,
so I didn't chime in when that was
happening.
I wanted to just call out like a flag for
something that we will need to consider
at some point.
And that's like the, what is it called,
like QSOA qualified service organization
agreement.
And so anything that touches Sud or
Medicaid is probably gonna have to have
that as an additional layer.
And this is more for like any like
provider regulations, whatever.
But I think we should somehow call it out
in the code or I mean, yeah,
in the in the rules so that like we don't
trip on ourselves when we hit that
insurance conversation later down the
road.
Nothing to vote on today.
Just like as we iterate this,
I think before we roll out,
we should probably have that conversation.
Yeah.
And I think the department would probably
have more to do with the.
I don't know that we can like establish
that agreement for them,
but I definitely think we can draw
attention to it.
Yeah.
And I'm not sure how it like would fold
into this part of the recommendation.
But if there's like a,
a provider who has like their BAA in
place with their patients and they are
receiving payments from Medicaid for any
part of their business,
I think Dominic probably has some insight
on this.
It's like I'm trying to understand the
link in here,
but there is a requirement for that
business to have an additional layer of
agreement with their patients.
I think that's how it works out.
Dom.
Yeah, Dominique.
Yeah, good morning, everybody.
I I mean,
this is something that is already
actually in place.
It doesn't necessarily need to be doesn't
necessarily need to be outlined here.
However,
all of the agreements that are there
would include it.
So including it in here and just saying
that it would also ensure to match with
the security rule is fine.
But that security rule is a part of HIPAA
itself.
So it's not necessarily doesn't need to
necessarily be outlined separately,
but if it helps people to feel a little
more protected,
there's not an issue with including it in.
It simply adds in another layer of
spelling it out for individuals,
especially for patients to say, look,
your,
your private health information needs to
be protected regardless of whether it's
paper, electronic or otherwise.
So to add it on in is not a problem,
especially from that standpoint.
And just to call it out,
but it is the security rule is a part of
HIPAA itself.
And and that was actually a part of why
the high tech to be added in really was
there.
And why I suggested that is just to give
patients and providers both sort of that
reminder of all of this information needs
to be protected no matter what.
I hope that helps that that totally makes
sense.
And I see it covered under high tech.
I'm,
my main concern was just downstream when
all of the insurance pieces fall together,
like calling out that due diligence,
like the program is 25,000 steps ahead.
And yeah, I think getting that insurance,
those Medicaid payments for a lot of
these conditions is, is massive.
But yeah, thank you.
Doesn't need to be, we don't need it.
I wouldn't recommend like refoating on
this thing or anything like that.
Just wanted to put the conversation out
there.
I appreciate it, thank you so much.
But is there any other comments before we
get to qualifying conditions?
All righty seeing none,
what does the committee believe are the
best conditions to start with?
I know one of the ones that I was
considering and has some of the best
evidence was just major depressive
disorder outside of treatment resistant
depression.
I definitely have been looking into OCD,
some other conditions,
but I definitely want to hear what the
committee is looking into and what y'all
would like to focus on 1st.
All right, looks like yeah, Chris, yeah.
I agree with you that we should look at
major depressive disorder.
And I don't know if just regular
depression has its own ICD or its own
codes,
but I don't really see a reason why
people should have to start with
pharmaceuticals if this could help them
through that process without without
taking medications.
So I would like to see just regular
depression as well.
Thank you, Major.
So it sounds like major depressing.
Yeah.
And major depressive disorder is just the
the government name of depression.
But yeah,
we could definitely look into that key.
Yeah, I, I agree with with Chris,
you know, having people,
if they don't want to be on
pharmaceuticals,
that might be difficult to get off of.
That would be nice if we don't have to
have the treatment resistant, you know,
if there's evidence that this could help.
And then I'll also say physical pain
could be, you know, helpful.
And then there's a whole, you know,
mounting body of evidence for brain
injuries.
So things like that could be added.
And, you know,
some of these things are overlapping.
Is it like working with the veterans here?
A lot of them is some kind of effect on
the brain from all the all the explosions.
But then there's also PTSD symptoms.
So sometimes those things go together.
Yeah,
I completely agree that sometimes it's
multifactorial leading to their symptoms.
So thank you.
We can definitely look at physical pain
in TBI.
Greg.
Agree.
Sorry, I was just gonna echo TBI.
I believe that was called out and that
weird,
weird meeting we had that was cast on
some weird television station that
nobody's ever heard of this weekend by
some orange guy with a bunch of thugs.
That felt like, yeah, anyways,
I'm pretty sure they called out TBI.
And I think getting ahead of that before
our state can enter the ibogaine
conversation and doing that with
psilocybin as an org,
as a full biomass would be really,
really interesting.
Thank you, Catherine.
Oh, sorry, your mic's enabled now.
There we go.
Definitely chronic pain.
I think that's important.
I also agree with TBI.
I was also thinking about,
I know they're doing a lot of research on
Parkinson's and that it's really helping
a lot with fibromyalgia as well.
So kind of looking at some, you know,
physical health issues that they're doing
work on.
I was also wondering about,
I know we're doing end of life,
but what about people with frozen grief,
right?
Like things that happened 10 years ago,
you know, maybe even, you know,
existential issues,
but really like focusing on this frozen
grief that I see this pretty often with
people,
especially if they've had multiple losses
throughout their life.
I just think that, you know,
we should consider expanding the end of
life so that it's not just people
currently experiencing it,
but things that, you know,
relate to the past.
Now,
you could also potentially see that as
PTSD because depending on, you know,
the situation.
But I just see that being a a big theme
that I see a lot with people.
Anyway, thank you.
Would a good word for that be existential
distress?
Like it doesn't necessarily have to be
the the that they are going to die.
It could have been just that they thought
they were going to die and or have some
other traumatic existential injury.
So would that be a good characterization
of what you were describing?
Yeah.
But I was also talking about people that
have experienced loss of others
throughout their life and they're stuck
like they are trigger.
I mean it again,
it could also be under PTSD.
But yeah,
people that have experienced near death
experiences themselves.
But also, you know,
just there's just a lot of grief.
I I just,
I'm thinking about like about 20
different patients in the past, you know,
six months that they,
they're stuck in their grief.
They can't move forward because they're
missing.
There's so much loss in their life.
And by the way, it's not always people.
It could be loss of a job,
loss of their identity, you know,
loss of health, like the disability.
Yeah, I like what Kate is saying.
Prolonged grief disorder.
That might be the way to put it.
Thank you.
I will go ahead and mark that down.
Chris, I'm,
I'm curious if tobacco cessation would be
included in, in our current,
what is it substance abuse protocols
would,
would tobacco qualify or would that have
to be separate?
In my humble opinion,
and ultimately the department will be the
one to to decide.
I believe nicotine use disorder would
also qualify for psilocybin use,
but I will defer until the department
makes that decision.
And if they decide contrary to that,
I would support adding nicotine use
disorder.
There have been a few credible studies on
it's effectiveness for that.
So Gregory or I think Catherine has her
hand up.
Oops, sorry Catherine, I already spoke.
So.
Oh, OK, there we go.
Catherine.
I think there there's something I've been
looking at called demoralization.
So the IT shows it's shown up in studies
around end of life and long term aid
survivors.
Essentially it's this triggered state
where you're discouraged, defeated,
unmotivated to the point you can't keep
trying.
It's like it, it, it's depression like,
like acute depression without like the
clinical definition of depression.
And it's,
it's showing up in a lot of research
lately.
And I think that might be a, a, a,
a hood to put that conversation under.
I have a small word salad,
things that haven't been touched,
cluster headaches, eating disorders,
postpartum depression,
the demoralization hood of conversations.
It's pretty bad, large.
I did want to echo the Alzheimer's and
Parkinson's conversation.
I think that's all I have on my current
list, Brenda.
Yes,
I was going to say Alzheimer's as well,
possibly autism.
This is something new that's being looked
at as well.
I think that along with autism comes
social anxieties, other types of fears.
So I think Alzheimer's is the other one
that was going to be talking about.
But Gregory did good job of answering
that will promote well saying you know
what he needed to say about Alzheimer's.
I think that would be further research to
be done.
Now I have a question.
Will New Mexico be on any of these
studies?
Will we be creating any studies here at
like one of the universities here?
I believe Larry Lehman is working on
research.
I think Dominic has more information than
I do on that if you would like to chime
in.
Sure.
Thank you, Ian.
And, and Brenda, it's a great question.
And as Ian was mentioning, you know,
Doctor Lehman over at UNM definitely has
some of his own studies that are,
are that he is Pi principal investigator
on and that he's working with.
So that would be part of it.
The other aspect is if the the research
fund does get funding in future years,
then that would be 1 area where this list
of items would be some of the areas that
we potentially could fund research in the
future.
But again,
that's all dependent upon that particular
fund getting funded.
So I hope that's helpful.
Yeah, Thank you.
And then, Catherine,
did you put your hand up or was it just
left up?
Yeah, no, I did.
OK, cool.
So, you know,
a couple things kind of going back to,
I guess the demoralization,
something that kind of stems out of that,
it's a little different.
It's a huge thing that I'm seeing with
clients right now.
And that's just moral injury.
I don't think there's any research around
it though, yet,
because I think that's kind of what our
our country's experiencing right now is a
lot of moral injury.
I also just wanted to mention,
and I don't know if this is the time to
bring it up or not,
but is this an area where we could bring
microdosing in at all or not?
Like it does that have to be brought in
in a different way?
I just am, you know,
just really seeing so many people wanting
micro dosing to be a part of this
experience,
which I understand the law is not written
for it,
but I'm just wondering if by looking at
new conditions, can we also bring in new,
you know,
the micro dosing piece at all or not?
So in terms of micro dosing,
it's not that it's not allowed,
it's that the law requires that we have a
preparation,
administration and integration session.
So as long as that is fulfilled,
we can have,
they can have a microdose of psilocybin.
So what I believe is being worked on in
dosage administration and clinical
practice would basically say that for
your first initial,
your preparation would be two sessions
with a total of 2 hours minimum and.
Then they are going to if you have
subsequent ones like let's say it's a
micro dose that you take recurring,
then you would you could get away with
less preparation sessions and potentially
combining some of those dosage
integration into singular ones to make it
possibly applicable.
But the current caveat and the law is
that we do have to have those three
sessions in there.
OK,
sorry to interject that in then I
apologize.
That's not sounds like that's not
relevant to this.
So I apologize.
No worries.
We all have questions.
I appreciate your thoughts.
And then, Gregory, Catherine,
I just sent you a bunch of stuff about
moral injury that I've been following.
And then I lost my train of thought.
Dominic was talking about.
What was Dominic talking about?
My brain.
Has anyone heard of ADHD?
Yes,
which is something that like I
specifically like so like the micro
dosing conversation is like massively
important for me,
but I definitely like am in the camp.
Can't I'm in camp table that because like,
once we get some normalization down,
then the, the,
the the flexibility and latitude to
design trials around micro dosing will
shift in future iterations of whatever
the approved locations Definitely kills
it.
I am aghast.
I literally cannot remember.
Brenda spoke before Dominic.
Yeah.
Brenda had asked Dominic if there's any
research going on in the state of New
Mexico.
He had explained what was going on with
Larry Lehman's study.
Got it.
I got it.
Thank you.
You triggered it.
You fired my brain cell,
my single remaining brain cell.
This is a crosswalk opportunity.
I'm curious if in the research and
continuous improvement group, we can so.
So when we have conditions,
we have 4 conditions.
There's gonna be overlapping conditions.
People will have additional potentially
like treatable conditions that are not
like the target of the therapy.
And so if we can call those out in like
an intake form and understand.
So we,
we have this list of 30 conditions that
we want to like consider let's like start
tracking those and see if there is like
tangentical improvement across those
things to help build bases for.
Yeah, like you can do,
you can do initial studies without even
like if you have this type of information
at a program level,
I think you could write papers based on
it and then get studies approved.
Anyways,
that was that was what I wanted to get
out.
Well, thank you.
I'm glad that you found your thought,
Eileen.
All right.
And your mic's enabled now.
Hey,
sorry for my I'm gonna say a lot of
things that I said in the chat,
but I couldn't unmute earlier,
so I apologize for that.
Yeah,
the restrictions that that this law
created do create a problem for treating
chronic pain.
Because most of the research that we have
right now says that like in order to
treat chronic pain,
especially conditions like headache
diseases,
you have to take a dose every five days,
which if you have to do a preparation and
an integration session before and after
each of those five days.
And that's going to cost you a couple
$1000.
It is not going to be affordable for
anybody.
And those sessions every five days
usually last for, you know,
quite some time, like, you know,
a month or two months in order to,
to get you out of that pain cycle that
you're in.
So chronic pain is probably going to to
be a challenge.
And the research that's out there right
now for chronic pain doesn't show that
those preparation and integration
sessions and the therapy component are
necessary to treat the chronic pain.
It's not that they're not also beneficial
because most people who live with chronic
pain also live with some kind of a mental
health issue that has been created by the
chronic pain that they live with or is
just comorbid with the chronic pain that
they live with.
But because of the, the,
the limitations of the law,
it's going to be a problem.
And it's going to be something that we're
going to have to address with the, the,
the, the training committee.
So that people don't go into these
sessions thinking I'm going to treat my
chronic pain by getting one or two
sessions of psychedelic assisted therapy
and, you know,
a preparation and an integrated session
and then become more hopeless when it
doesn't work for them.
And that's not to say that I don't agree
with what Gregory says,
that we should be tracking it in Colorado.
They're going to start working to track
these other things,
whether people are having improvement in
their chronic pain.
Because it could be that one or two
sessions is all somebody needs to treat
their low back pain or their spinal
stenosis or something like that.
We don't know enough yet to know that the
most robust clinical trials are around
cluster headache and migraine right now.
But the other thing that I wanted to
point out is that there's some research
about autoimmune conditions,
especially Lyme,
that has been coming to light recently.
And so I also think that those conditions
should be included in our list.
Thank you so much.
All righty.
Any others?
All righty.
So we still,
we have quite a few conditions that I
heard brought up today.
We have physical pain, TBI, Parkinson's,
fibromyalgia, major depressive disorder,
existential distress,
prolonged reef disorder, demoralization,
cluster headaches, PPD, Alzheimer's,
Parkinson's and autism.
So I heard major depressive disorder and
chronic pain the most.
Would you guys like to go into that in
detail next meeting?
Cool.
All right, I saw some yeses in the chat.
So we will go ahead and look over chronic
pain and I said Alzheimer's, right?
Chronic pain and Alzheimer's for the next.
Gregory, if we're going to do Alzheimer's,
can we just lump Parkinson's into that as
a broader like multi like categorization
of things?
So yeah, we can do MDD, Alzheimer's,
Parkinson's.
And then Eileen had a comment.
Maybe neurological conditions overall.
Yeah,
I think that's what I was trying to say.
Thank you, Eileen.
Sure.
All righty.
So we will go over neurological
conditions and major depressive disorder
at the next meeting.
We will go ahead and set that.
No.
All right.
Does May 4th at 9:00 AM work for the
department?
Oh, Gregory had another comment.
Sorry.
Oh, no, just while you were writing,
I was wondering like,
are we at the point in this committee
where like we get to like just get deep
divey and start talking about the future?
Sure.
No, like, like if we're,
if we're going into like a series of
meetings where we're gonna like dig into
some of these conditions,
I think we have an incredible like body
of people here that will have wonderful,
like this will become my favorite
meetings just to get information from
people that like that are in this room
doing so much work here.
So yeah,
I'd be really interested to see if the
next month or two or is is that's what
the goal of this group is or if we're
gonna keep working in tandem on other
stuff as well.
So as far as the patient qualification
committee bylaws go,
we have achieved all of the objection
objectives minus the initial qualifying
conditions.
So this will be the the deep dive into
what specific things,
what research is out there,
What research goes against this?
Is there any biases?
What is the all of why does this help
this condition?
Why should it be recommended?
Is this common practice, things like that?
Maybe not common practice,
that is probably the wrong word,
but common research context could be.
Yeah, Yeah.
So it it'll be that part,
the actual assessment of analysis because
this committee has produced most of our
deliver all of our deliverables minus the
initial qualifying conditions.
Awesome.
Can I throw out a resource?
Sure.
Find it.
I'll come back and I'll come back with
that.
Perfect.
And then I once again,
I'm gonna ask the department is May 4th.
What's that?
What's the day?
I said May 4th available for you guys at
9:00 AM Yes, yes,
it is currently available.
So snag it before someone else does EQ
9:00 AM to and then we'll do 11 since
we're going over a brand 9 to 11 since
we're going over a couple of conditions,
then we're gonna get in the weeds, cool.
And then as soon as Gregory gets us our
resource, then we can adjourn.
I'm gonna drop it in the chat here.
But after the thing that happened this
weekend from somebody who doesn't deserve
the attention, I did a very deep dive on,
you know,
like where clinical trials are for which
treatments and which like Pantheon of
Classics and other psychedelics.
But this organization has this incredible
map of every clinical trial and where
it's at in its progress and like links to
the deeper research.
And this was a fascinating deep dive.
I encourage anyone who hasn't to check
out the Psychedelic Alpha website.
Well, thank you.
I definitely will be checking it out
myself.
But thank you everyone for coming and
participating today.
I appreciate all of your input and for
spending in the morning of 4/20 with us.
Have a great, you know, rest of your week.
It is Monday, so make the best out of it.
Thank you guys so much for coming and
thank you again everybody.